### KYLE WUELLNER

Shawnee, KS 66216

Phone: (913) 206-6963 | Email: kyle.m.wuellner@gmail.com LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/kyle-wuellner | Github: www.github.com/kwuellner Portfolio: kwuellner.github.io

### SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer educated at the University of Kansas' coding bootcamp. Coming from a photography background strengths include HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Love using creative side to develop a website that is not only pleasing but offers a good UX experience. Have experience working with teams to collaborate, problem solve and execute an idea, both professionally and academically. Looking forward to pulling from past work experience and education to develop new projects and websites with a team.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Node.Js | Express | JavaScript | jQuery | React | GIT | GitHub | MongoDB | MySQL |Firebase Handlebars | HTML | CSS | Bootstrap | Media Queries | API's | Heroku | RESTful API's Mongoose | JSON | Excel | Adobe XD

### **P**ROJECTS

**Bamazon** | github.com/kwuellner/bamazon

- A storefront shop that allows you to purchase items and track your inventory.
- Personally worked on all aspects of this program.
- Node.js and MySql

FreshAir | github.com/kwuellner/project2 | kwuellner.com/github.io/project2

- Travel website that builds a vacation around your response to survey questions
- Front-end development, UI, and some back-end authentication
- HTML. CSS

### **Liri Node App** | github.com/kwuellner/liri-node-app

- App to search for concerts in town, songs on Spotify and movie information
- Personally worked on all aspects
- Node.is, Moment, Doteny, Axios, multiple APIs

### EXPERIENCE

## **Zimmer Biomet**; Lenexa, KS *Inventory Control Coordinator*

12/2013 - Present

Assist in managing inventory for a multimillion dollar territory for multiple accounts like large hospitals, regional medical centers, and privately owned surgical centers. Monitoring supply and demand for trauma, extremities, sports medicine, and biologic products. Managing and forecasting the distribution of implants and instruments.

- Working with a team to process and oversee 500+ surgeries a month to ensure all surgeries are covered
- Provide sales support for over 30 sales associates across Kansas and western Missouri that has resulted in yearly growth for both sales and acquiring new accounts
- Forecasting future surgeries in order to get any products ordered in on time
- Received 9 Impact Awards, which are given to employees that show exemplary service

### Suture Express; Lenexa, KS

11/2012 - 12/2013

Customer Order Fulfilment

Scanned and shipped various suture materials for hospitals and surgery centers located around the country. Visually inspected all items to ensure none are damaged. Restocked shelves with incoming products.

- Verified that all items were being shipped with the correct packing slip and to the correct address so that all customers get the exact products ordered
- Worked efficiently but quickly to ensure quarterly quotas were exceeded for both units per hour picked and error free metrics, 120+ units per hour and under 3 errors
- Made sure all orders were pulled and shipped on time so customers were not without products

### FedEx Ground; Shawnee, KS

11/2011 - 12/2013

Package Handler/Sorter

Worked in a fast paced environment loading multiple trucks for local deliveries. Pulled packages off a conveyor belt making sure all packages were loaded on the vehicle and in the proper order according to the drivers stops.

- Managed and monitored the belt so that all packages were moving at an appropriate speed
- Trained employees, both newly hired and existing employees wanting to become more efficient
- Organized packages on the truck so that labels were all clearly visible for the driver
- Arrived early to make sure all stations are ready before the shift starts

# **Schmuhl Brothers International;** Kansas City, KS 8/2011 - 10/2012 & 2/2010 - 12/2010 *Inventory/Billing*

Responsible for billing and inventory for all rail containers. Worked with various rail yards to ensure all containers are being sent to correct port. Daily contact with businesses for billing and information on order status.

 Managed products and inventory in the warehouse to prevent any overages and shortages

- Evaluated expiry dates for applicable products to adhere to FIFO (First In, First Out) in order to prevent any extra costs that would have been incurred for expired products
- Clear verbal and written communication with billing department to guarantee trailers were billed properly and were sent to the correct rail yard
- Visually verified all trucks and containers were filled/loaded with the correct product that had been ordered
- Accurate and detailed data entry in order for products to be tracked by the company, customers, and also for customs documents

### **EDUCATION**

Full-Stack Web Development Certificate - University of Kansas; Overland Park, KS